<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<!DOCTYPE book PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.4//EN"
    "http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/4.4/docbookx.dtd">

<book lang='en'>

<bookinfo>
<title>SafeBrowsing4OTRS</title>
<edition>Adds a Google Safe Browsing check to the TicketZoom to inspect all links in an article for possible security risks. Version 1.0.0</edition>

<copyright>
<year>2013</year>
<holder>Marc Nilius, otrs@marcnilius.de, http://www.marcnilius.de</holder>
</copyright>

<date>26.10.2013</date>

<legalnotice>
    <para>GNU AFFERO GENERAL PUBLIC LICENSE Version 3, November 2007</para>
    <para>This work is copyrighted by Marc Nilius, http://www.marcnilius.de.</para>
    <para>Build Date: 26.10.2013</para>
</legalnotice>

</bookinfo>

<preface id="preface" >
    <title>Preface</title>
    <para>
        SafeBrowsing4OTRS is an OTRS module to check the articles of your tickets against the Google Safe
        Browsing database for potential malware and phishing links.
    </para>
</preface>

<chapter>
    <title>Feature List</title>
    <section>
        <title>Google Safe Browsing database</title>
        <para>
            The Google Safe Browsing database is used by Google to warn users about potentially unsafe websites that deliver malware
            or are some kind of phishing website. These information are used in the Google search results and also in the
            Google Chrome browser or Mozilla Firefox browser, if you try to vitis such a website.
        </para>
        <para>
            This OTRS module uses the Google Safe Broswing database to warn the agents about potentially unsafe links or URLs
            in articles of OTRS tickets, e.g. incoming emails of clients or spam.
        </para>
    </section>
    <section>
        <title>Warnings shown in the TicketZoom</title>
        <para>
            The module checks the links and URLs in the ticket articles and shows a warn message if any of the checked websites
            are found in the Google Safe Browsing database. The module does not prevent the agent from clicking the link and visiting the
            website!
        </para>
        <para>
            Please be aware of the fact, that sometimes the database has false entries of websites that are completely safe but are listed
            as unsafe. Visiting all links and using this module for information about potentially unsafe websites is at your own risk.
        </para>
        <para>
            To always have the latest database updates, the results of a check are not cached in the OTRS database. The module needs
            an active internet connection on the OTRS server to connect to the Google database.
        </para>
    </section>
</chapter>

<chapter>
    <title>System Requirements</title>
    <section>
        <title>Framework</title>
        <para>The following OTRS framework is required:</para>
        <para>
            OTRS Version 3.2.x and Version 3.3.x.
        </para>
        <para>
            This module uses PubSub event hooks, that were introduced with OTRS 3.2.0 beta5, and does not work
            in earlier versions of OTRS.
        </para>
    </section>
    <section>
        <title>Google Safe Browsing database API key</title>
        <para>
            In order to get access to the Google Safe Browsing database, you need an API key. This API key is for free.
            You can get your API key here: <ulink url="https://developers.google.com/safe-browsing/key_signup">https://developers.google.com/safe-browsing/key_signup</ulink>
        </para>
    </section>
</chapter>

<chapter>
    <title>Installation</title>
    <para>The following instructions explain how to install the package.</para>
    <section>
        <title>Admin Interface</title>
        <para>
            Please use the following URL to install the package utilizing the admin
            interface (please note that you need to be in the admin group).
        </para>
        <para>
            <ulink url="http://localhost/otrs/index.pl?Action=AdminPackageManager">
                http://localhost/otrs/index.pl?Action=AdminPackageManager
            </ulink>
        </para>
    </section>
    <section>
        <title>Command Line</title>
        <para>
            Whenever you cannot use the Admin Interface for whatever reason,
            you may use the following command line tool (&quot;bin/otrs.PackageManager.pl&quot;)
            instead.
        </para>
        <para>
        <screen>
            shell> bin/otrs.PackageManager.pl  -a install -p /path/to/$Name-$Version.opm
        </screen>
        </para>
    </section>
</chapter>

<chapter>
    <title>Configuration</title>
    <para>The package can be configured via the SysConfig in the Admin Interface. The following configuration options are available:</para>
    <section>
        <title>SafeBrowsing::Active.</title>
        <para>Group: SafeBrowsing4OTRS, Subgroup: Settings.</para>
        <para>Activates Safe Browsing feature.</para>
    </section>
    <section>
        <title>SafeBrowsing::APIKey.</title>
        <para>Group: SafeBrowsing4OTRS, Subgroup: Settings.</para>
        <para>The Google Safe Browsing API key. You can get your API key here: https://developers.google.com/safe-browsing/key_signup.</para>
    </section>
    <section>
        <title>SafeBrowsing::CheckOnlyExternalMessages.</title>
        <para>Group: SafeBrowsing4OTRS, Subgroup: Settings.</para>
        <para>Only check incoming messages for potentially unsafe links and URLs.</para>
    </section>
    <section>
        <title>SafeBrowsing::FadeOutMessage.</title>
        <para>Group: SafeBrowsing4OTRS, Subgroup: Settings.</para>
        <para>If the module does not find any potentially unsafe links and URLs, fade out the info message after some seconds.</para>
    </section>
    <section>
        <title>SafeBrowsing::FadeOutTime.</title>
        <para>Group: SafeBrowsing4OTRS, Subgroup: Settings.</para>
        <para>The number of milliseconds to wait until the message will be faded out (1000 milliseconds = 1 second).</para>
    </section>
    <section>
        <title>Frontend::Module###SafeBrowsing4OTRS.</title>
        <para>Group: SafeBrowsing4OTRS, Subgroup: Frontend::Agent::ModuleRegistration.</para>
        <para>Frontend module registration for SafeBrowsing4OTRS.</para>
    </section>
    <section>
        <title>Frontend::Output::FilterElementPre###OutputFilterPreSafeBrowsing4OTRS.</title>
        <para>Group: SafeBrowsing4OTRS, Subgroup: OutputFilter.</para>
        <para>Output filter to add SafeBrowsing to the TicketZoom.</para>
    </section>
    <section>
        <title>Frontend::Module###AgentTicketZoom.</title>
        <para>Group: Ticket, Subgroup: Frontend::Agent::ModuleRegistration.</para>
        <para>Frontend module registration for the agent interface.</para>
    </section>
</chapter>

<chapter>
    <title>ChangeLog</title>
    <para>
        Version 1.0.0: First public release.
    </para>
</chapter>

<chapter>
    <title>Contacts</title>
    <para>Marc Nilius, Mail: otrs@marcnilius.de, Website: http://www.marcnilius.de</para>
</chapter>

</book>
